m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：薄荷小瑾    愚公移山
翻译：斑驳的小屋    临风公子
■
校对：丁丁猫哒    后期：Sung1219
上
Move!
现在可是生死抉择  詹姆斯
It's life or death now, James.
也就是说  在洛克维尔监狱里
By that, I mean you're doing one or the other
你只能选择生或者死
up in Rockview.
这是地方检察官  罗丁
This here is District Attorney Rodin.
你想知道他在想什么吗
Want to know what he's wondering?
他在想你是会像男子汉一样走进死囚监狱
Whether you're gonna walk like a man or cry like a pussy
还是会像娘们儿一样哭哭啼啼
on your way to the death house.
地方检察官喜欢直接宣判死刑
See, the D.A. likes the needle,
而我
whereas me,
希望你这样的人能长命百岁
I like to see a man like you live a long life
可以慢慢折磨你
with all your teeth knocked out.
把你折磨得半死不活
Passed around till a brother can't tell your fart from a yawn.
虽然我不知道你是什么样的人
Now, I don't know what kind of man you are,
也不知道你更喜欢哪种命运
which of these two fates you prefer,
但罗丁是个仁慈的人
but Rodin here is a generous fellow.
他同意让你自己选
He's willing to let you take your pick.
如果你不想耗时费力
If you save us and this city a long and costly trial,
那就放弃请律师直接认罪吧
waive your right to counsel and confess, right now.
16个小时
Sixteen hours.
刷新纪录了吧  探长
Has to be some kind of record, Detective.
你写的是什么
What the hell is this?
杰克・雷彻又是谁
Who the hell is Jack Reacher?
杰克・雷彻
Jack Reacher,
就叫杰克  没有中间名  就像个幽灵
born Jack, not John, no middle name, is a ghost.
没有驾照  不论是过去还是现在
No driver's licence, current or expired.
一直都没有住址
No residence, current or former.
没有信用卡  也没有信用纪录
No credit cards, no credit history.
没有邮箱  不用手机  不发电子邮件
No P.O. Box, cell phone, e-mail.
没有任何记录
Nothing.
你至少告诉我他是谁吧
Can you at least tell me who he is?
我可以告诉你他原来是干什么的  军人世家
Well, I can tell you who he was. Blood military.
在海外的军事基地出生长大
Born and raised on bases abroad.
母亲是法国人  父亲是军人
Mother was a French national, father in the Corps.
第一次来美国是去西点军校上学
His first trip to the United States was to attend West Point.
四年后出境执行任务
Four years later, he ships out for good.
去过伊拉克  阿富汗  巴尔干等地
Iraq. Afghanistan. The Balkans. You name it.
获得了很多荣誉
Served with distinction.
银星勋章  铜星勋章  战功勋章
Silver Star, Bronze Star, Legion of Merit.
国防高级服务勋章  这个没听说过
Defence Superior Service Medal? Had to look that one up.
还有一枚紫心勋章  他主要在宪兵队工作
And a Purple Heart. He spent the bulk of his service
总而言之
in the Military Police. By all accounts,
他是一名出色的调查员
a brilliant investigator.
当然  也很爱惹是生非
Apparently, a troublemaker, too.
他被降职为上尉
Demoted to Captain.
后来又一路升回少校
Worked his way back to Major.
两年前  从部队退役
Then two years ago, he musters out.
他几乎一辈子都混在军队
After a literal lifetime in the military,
却突然退伍了
he just up and quits. And then,
之后生平第二次
for only the second time in his life,
他来到美国  从此就销声匿迹了
he enters the United States and simply disappears.
是不是死了
Dead, maybe?
根据社保记录
Not according to Social Security
和弗吉尼亚州一家银行的记录来看  应该没有
and a bank account in Virginia.
每月他的抚恤金发放后
His pension is deposited monthly
都会有人不定期地支取
and someone is making the
都是通过电汇方式
occasional withdrawal. All wire transfers.
我的权限只能查到这么多
I can't find out where without a federal warrant.
那他不能开车也不能乘坐飞机
Well, he can't drive or fly.
至少不是用自己的身份
At least not under his real name.
-有没有什么犯罪记录  -没有
-Any warrants? -Record's clean.
不可能  这样神秘难寻的人  肯定犯过什么事
Come on! A guy this hard to find? Gotta be wanted for something.
他没有任何犯罪记录
His record is clean.
这样的话
So,
我们怎么才能找到这个雷彻呢
how do we find this Reacher?
很明显我们找不到他  除非他自己现身
Obviously, you don't find this guy unless he wants to be found.
打扰一下  有位叫杰克・雷彻的人想见你
Excuse me, sir. There's a Jack Reacher here to see you.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
我找詹姆斯・巴尔
James Barr.
现在你看到他了  你怎么认识他的
So, now you've seen him. How do you know him?
为什么他没有受到保护性监禁
Why wasn't he in protective custody?
那是个小疏忽
That was an oversight.
更像是那些势利小人把他送入虎口的
More like some Corrections flunky threw him to the wolves.
可能是吧
Just as likely.
但是事情已经发生  我们也无法挽回了
But it's done and we can't undo it.
那现在怎么办
So what happens now?
他还在昏迷中
Well, now he's in a coma.
他醒来以后我们会再审问他
We'll try him when he wakes up.
如果他能醒来的话
If he wakes up.
好吧  该你说了雷彻
Okay? Now it's your turn, Reacher.
他为什么要你做证人
Why did he call you as a witness?
我认为他不会
I don't believe he did.
但是他指名要你
Well, I believe he asked for you by name.
我能不能看下证物
Any chance I could look at the evidence?
不行  除非你先回答我几个问题
No way. Not till you answer some questions.
再会
Nice meeting you.
雷彻先生
Mr Reacher.
-雷彻先生  -等一下  站住
-Mr Reacher! -Hey, stop! Stop right there!
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
我带你来看巴尔  你告诉我你知道的信息
I take you to Barr, you tell me what you know.
我知道你说他杀了五个人  现在昏迷中
I know you say he shot five people, I know he's in a coma.
我还知道三英里外就有个汽车站
I know there's a bus station three miles away
我用24分钟就能走到
and I can walk there in 24 minutes.
你就这么撇下你朋友走了
So you're just going to walk out on your friend?
-他不是我朋友  -那他为什么找你来
-He's not my friend. -Why'd he ask for you, then?
和他枪杀五个人是同样的原因  他疯了
Well, same reason he shot five people, he's crazy.
等一下
Hey. Hold on.
放手
Don't do that.
你们俩真是卑鄙啊
Well, this is a new low, even for both of you.
我不在你们不能审问我的当事人
You do not talk to my client without me present.
你应该知道
You know that.
我们没审问你的当事人
We weren't talking to your client.
他还在昏迷中  拜托
He's in a coma, for Christ's sakes.
你是巴尔的辩护律师
You're Barr's attorney?
这是海伦・罗丁  这是杰克・雷彻
Helen Rodin, Jack Reacher.
-杰克・雷彻  -海伦・罗丁
-Jack Reacher? -Helen Rodin.
对  她是地方检察官的女儿
Yeah, she's the District Attorney's daughter.
这事说来话长
It's a good story, actually.
愿闻其详
I'd like to hear it.
你们怎么找到他的  他们怎么找到你的
How'd you find him? How'd they find you?
你们不能和他接触  一天就犯了两次规
You can't be talking to this man. Two strikes in one day.
-事实不是这样的  -是他找的我们
-It's not what it looks like. -He came to us.
-你去了地方检察官办公室  -这犯法吗
-You went to the D. A? -Is there a law against that?
目前不犯法
None you're currently breaking.
算了吧  别弄得这么尴尬
Come on, before this gets awkward. Now, hey.
快说句法庭见  拜托
Say, "See you in court." For me.
再见  探长
Goodbye, Detective.
-很高兴见到你  -我也是
-Weird meeting you. -Likewise.
走吧
Let's go.
那么
So...
那么  你就是杰克・雷彻
So, you're Jack Reacher.
-那么你是地方检察官的女儿  -天啊  拜托
-So you're the D.A.'s daughter. -Oh, Jesus. Please.
-这合法吗  -幸运的是  合法
-Is that even legal? -Fortunately.
-怎么会这样  -出庭作证我就告诉你
-How does that happen? -I'll tell you after deposition.
你不会想要我出庭作证的
You don't want to depose me.
没办法  你是我唯一的被告证人
Oh, well, you're my only defence witness.
我不是被告的证人
I'm not a defence witness.
可是你的朋友詹姆斯认为你是
Your friend James thinks you are.
他不是我的朋友
He's not my friend.
为什么人们都认为他是我的朋友
Why does everyone assume that?
那他为什么会找你
Well, why else would he ask for you
你又为什么会来帮他
and why would you come here to help him?
我不是来帮他的  我是来收拾他的
I didn't come here to help him. I came here to bury him.
林斯基
Linsky.
杰克・雷彻到底是什么人
Who the hell is Jack Reacher?
你到底为什么这么难找
So why are you so hard to find?
你们不可能找得到我
I'm impossible to find.
为什么
Why is that?
你可以这样认为
Well, you could say it started
这是我的职业习惯
out as an exercise and became an addiction.
你是在逃跑吗
Are you on the run?
我的车快开了  你最好快点  律师小姐
My bus is leaving. You better hurry, counsellor.
你是怎么认识詹姆斯・巴尔的
How do you know James Barr?
-你又为什么为他辩护  -因为我是律师
-Why are you representing him? -I'm a lawyer.
公设辩护律师也是律师
So is a public defender,
也能帮巴尔洗脱罪名
with just as much chance of clearing Barr.
我并不是要帮他脱罪
I'm not trying to clear him,
只是想让他免于死刑罢了
I am just trying to keep him off death row.
-通过证明他有精神病  -这是一个方法
-By proving he's insane? -Well, that's one option.
跟你爸爸作对是因为
And sticking it to your father because...
不是我爸爸  是地方检察官办公室
No. Not my father. The Office of the District Attorney.
因为小时候他们没有给你买小马吗
Because the Office of the District Attorney never bought you a pony.
罗丁检察官在死刑案上从没失败过
D.A. Rodin's never lost a capital case.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
他诉讼工作做得好
Impeccable tailoring.
是因为他从不打无准备之仗
He never picks a fight he can't win.
是个传奇人物啊
Worked for the Red Baron.
这里所有的嫌疑犯都会面临两个选择
Every murder suspect in this town is given a choice.
要么认罪  要么死刑
Confess or face death.
面对这样一个常胜地方检察官
Against a D.A. Who never loses.
有些我们事务所认为无罪的人
My firm has reason to believe more than one innocent man
都没有申辩就直接认罪了
has gone down without a fight.
我明白了
Oh, I get it.
你是个理想主义者
You're an idealist.
不  我是个和平主义者
No. I'm a pacifist.
真是高尚
It's a noble crusade.
但这次不用了  相信我  詹姆斯・巴尔有罪
But this is not the fight. Trust me. James Barr's guilty.
你都还没看过证物
You haven't even seen the evidence.
我们的谈话是保密的吧
Is this a privileged conversation?
当然  这是个客户会面
Of course, it's a client conference.
你所说的所有的话都是保密的
Nothing you say here can be repeated.
有四种人会去参军
There are four types of people who join the military.
一种是为了家族荣耀
For some, it's a family trade.
有些是爱国者  迫切想要为国服务
Others are patriots, eager to serve.
还有一些仅仅是把它当成一份工作
Next, you have those who just need a job.
另外还有一些人
Then there's the kind who
就是为了给杀人找个正当的理由
want a legal means of killing other people.
詹姆斯・巴尔就属于最后一种
James Barr was one of those.
他是一名狙击手
He made sniper.
刻苦训练  每周两千发
Trained hard. Two thousand rounds a week.
每一枪都要求
And with every shot, he's taught to visualise
瞄准脑门
the base of a man's skull through his reticle.
就是骨髓和脊柱交汇的地方
The sweet spot where the medulla meets the spine.
然后看到血雾喷出
Visualise that puff of pink mist.
终于  他被派往伊拉克
Finally, he's deployed to Iraq.
做掩护狙击手
He's put on overwatch.
每天他就通过瞄准镜观察每一个平民百姓
All day long he stares through a scope at civilians.
妇女
Women.
儿童
Children.
日复一日  就这样过了两年
Day in, day out, for two long years
却没有收到一次开枪的命令
without ever once being cleared to fire a single shot.
后来就要撤兵了
Then comes the drawdown.
对詹姆斯・巴尔来说  战争已经结束了
For James Barr, the war's over.
每周两千发的练习
Two thousand rounds a week.
军旅生涯中一共25万次的训练
A quarter million rounds in his career,
却从未对人开过一枪
not one at a human target.
你会感到饥渴  感到欲火中烧
You've been hungry. You've been horny.
心痒难耐却无法抓挠
You've had an itch you can't scratch.
想象那种感觉  日复一日  年复一年
Imagine that feeling. Days. Weeks. Years.
想象一下这种感觉经历了二十五万次
Imagine that feeling times 200,000, plus 50,000 more.
想象一下在53摄氏度的高温下
Imagine it's 130 degrees
明天你就要回家了
on the deck and tomorrow you're going home
你明白  如果你今天再不止痒的话
and you know if you don't scratch that itch now,
这种抓心挠肺的感觉就会一直跟着你
you never will.
你需要释放
You need a release.
你得找个目标
You need a target.
你从没想过要谁做目标
And the who of it never once enters your mind.
他做得干净利落
He covered his tracks well,
跟正常人一样
just like sane people do.
他差点就逍遥法外
He almost got away with it, too.
但我抓住了他  他也认罪了
But I caught him. And he confessed.
那为什么他没有进监狱呢
So why didn't he go to prison?
巴尔不知道的是
What Barr didn't know that day
他杀的这四个承包商
was the four civilian contractors he'd picked off
周末刚参加过所谓的强奸晚会
just spent the weekend at what they call a rape-rally.
二十八个女性  年龄大的54岁  小的只有11岁
It was 28 women, ages 54 on down to 11.
这些还只是
Those were just the ones
我在结案前找到的
I could find before the case was shut down.
挖得越深  现实就越丑陋
See, the deeper I dug, the uglier it got.
连续七年这个团体都是圆满完成任务
And after seven long years of "Mission Accomplished,"
有人希望
someone in the corporation
隐瞒真相
just wanted the whole thing to end quietly.
因此他们就借战争的烟雾
So they chalked it up to the fog of war,
将这些杀人案件抹得了无痕迹
made the murders go away.
这都是机密信息
This is classified information.
这也是我们谈话要保密的原因
And that's why the privilege.
但你已经准备告诉地方检察官了
But you were ready to tell this to the D.A.
我上次见巴尔的时候  我向他保证过
The last time I saw Barr, I made him a promise.
当我在新闻上看到他时  我就来兑现承诺了
And when I saw his name on the news, I came here to keep it.
-但是现在没必要了  -你怎么能确定呢
-But now I know I don't have to. -How can you be sure?
你连证物都没看
You still haven't seen the evidence.
但你父亲已经看过了  他从不打无准备之仗
Your father has. And he doesn't pick a fight he can't win.
巴尔不能再次逃脱罪责了
Barr's not getting away with murder again.
还是有可能的
He might.
他在监禁中受到了严重的脑损伤
He suffered a severe brain injury in state custody.
他醒来的时候  如果他能醒来的话
When he wakes up, if he wakes up,
他可能已经忘了这次枪击案
he may not remember the event,
忘了所有的事
he may not remember anything at all.
那就不是詹姆斯・巴尔是否有罪的问题了
And this case won't be about James Barr's guilt or innocence.
而是他能不能出庭受审的问题了
It'll be about his ability to stand trial.
听了我说的这些  你还想为他辩护吗
After everything I just told you, you still want to defend him?
我想他得到公正的审判
I want to see he gets a fair trial.
你说他在巴格达认罪了
You said he confessed in Baghdad.
可这次他还没有认罪
He didn't confess this time.
-因为这次他更自信  -因为这次他找了你
-This time he knows better. -This time he asked for you.
我想知道原因
I want to know why.
你也想知道原因  我能看得出来你的煎熬
You want to know why. I can see it's eating you.
而你又不能问巴尔原因
And you can't ask Barr,
地方检察官又不让你看证物
and the D.A. Won't let you see the evidence.
我的主调查员
My lead investigator has
可以接触到证物  所有的证物
complete access to the evidence. All of it.
你的调查员在哪儿
So where's your lead investigator?
正打算坐车出城呢
About to catch a bus out of town.
谢谢你的咖啡  律师小姐
Thanks for the coffee, counsellor.
你知道你要我看的不仅仅是证物
You understand you're not just asking me to look at the evidence.
而是个冷血杀手
You're asking me to look at a cold-blooded killer.
我明知这个人有罪  你却想让他免于死刑
A man I know to be guilty. A man you want to keep off death row.
你要求我客观地看待他
And you're asking me to look at him objectively.
不错  这正是我要求的
Yes, that is what I'm asking.
可以  但有个条件
I'll do it. On one condition.
什么
Name it.
你也要客观地看待那些受害者
You have to look at the victims objectively.
那你要我怎么做呢
How do you suggest I do that?
-你找谁  -法里奥先生吗
-Yes? -Mr Farrior?
我是海伦・罗丁  我们通过电话
I'm Helen Rodin. We spoke on the phone.
想起来了
Of course.
你说你在为那个杀人
You said you're defending the man that ki...
那个人辩护
That man.
是的  我是詹姆斯・巴尔的代表律师
I represent James Barr, yes.
你想了解有关我女儿的事情
And you have questions about my daughter?
是的
I do.
为什么
What for?
我想更好地了解一下那些被害人平时
I was hoping to get a better sense of who the victims were as...
他们日常生活中是什么样子的
That is to say, who they were as people. As human beings.
以你的身份来说  这样做挺奇怪的  不是吗
That's a bit unusual, considering your position, isn't it?
确实是
That is true.
通常情况下  我们都尽可能让陪审团
Normally someone in my position would want the jury
少了解那些
to know as little as possible about the...
你的当事人杀死的受害者
The people that your client killed.
无情杀死的人
In cold blood.
你和其他受害人家庭谈过了吗
Have you spoken with the other families?
是的  跟那些愿意跟我交谈的谈过了
Yeah, some. The ones who would speak with me.
进来吧
Come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
克丽丝的工作是保姆
Chrissie was a nanny.
那天她要照看一个小女孩
She had a little girl with her that day.
我知道
Yes, I know.
你会去找那个小孩谈话吗
Are you gonna go talk with that child?
不  当然不会  我
No, of course not. I...
为什么呢
Why not?
-我觉得那样太  -太麻木不仁
-Well, I think it would be... -Insensitive?
还是不太合适
Inappropriate?
所有有关我女儿的材料
Everything that you want to know about my daughter
都在这里了
is right here.
《公报》上写得很清楚
The Gazette did a nice piece on her.
还有不清楚的可以去读一下她的讣告
Her obituary does the rest.
谢谢你  我一定会认真读的
Thank you. I'll definitely have a look.
罗丁小姐  你是个好律师吗
You a good attorney, Miss Rodin?
-这真的不适合我来  -请
-That's not really for me to... -Just
回答问题
answer the question.
是的  我认为自己是一名好律师
Yes, I suppose I am pretty good.
出色到可以让他免于死刑
Good enough to keep that man off death row?
其实
You know,
我想我该走了
I think maybe I should go.
你坐好
You stay where you are.
那个男人该死  罗丁小姐
That man deserves to die, Miss Rodin.
你为什么要为他辩护呢
Why would you defend him?
我明白我犯了个很严重的错误
I can see that I have made a terrible mistake.
真是非常抱歉  我保证再也不来打搅你了
And I'm very, very sorry and I promise I won't bother you again.
爸爸
Hello, Dad.
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我在  什么
What am I... What?
是真的吗
Is it true?
你去找受害者的家人  你一个人
You're talking to the victims' families? You? Alone?
你怎么知道的  你怎么知道我在这里的
How do you know that? How did you find me here?
我是地方检察官  这是我的工作
I'm the District Attorney. It's my business to know.
你还是没回答我的问题
That's not an answer.
并不是只有你有出色的调查员  海伦
Well, you're not the only one with crack investigators, Helen.
不错  我知道雷彻
That's right. I know about Reacher.
你的调查员是个退伍兵
Your lead investigator is a war veteran
而且还失踪了两年
who's been missing for the last two years.
你怎么能保证他的心态正常呢
How can you vouch for his state of mind?
你怎么能相信他说的话呢
How can you trust anything he tells you?
你不了解他
You don't know the man.
那你说  他知道你不会给他付工资吗
Tell me this, does he know you can't pay him?
他知道你们事务所根本不想接这个案子吗
That your own firm didn't want this case?
他知道根本没人想接这个案子吗
That nobody wants this case?
你的当事人昏迷之前也根本没和你交谈过
You never even spoke to your client before he wound up in a coma.
听我说  听着
Oh, now listen to me! Listen.
听着  我是以你父亲的身份在跟你说
Listen, I'm speaking as your father.
不论过去我们有什么分歧
Whatever our differences have been in the past,
你现在一定要听我说
you gotta listen to me now.
你犯了一个很严重的错误
You're making a terrible mistake.
这个案子你不可能赢的
You cannot win this case.
你会毁了自己的事业  为什么  到底为什么
You're going to ruin your career. Why? For what?
为了伤害我  还是为了改变我
To hurt me? To change me?
-海伦  -别碰我
-Helen... -Don't touch me!
多谢你让我查看证物
Thanks for letting me take a look.
我们很喜欢犯罪嫌疑人的朋友
Hey. We love it when friends of the accused
来插手我们的工作
try to tear our work to shreds.
他不是我的朋友
He's not my friend.
随你怎么说吧  找到什么疑点了吗
So you keep saying. Find any holes?
其实你们根本没必要把他送到医院的
Well, you didn't have to put him in the hospital.
除了这点  其他做得都不错  案情简单明了
Other than that, damn fine police work. It's open and shut.
没办法  犯罪现场就像一个金矿  证物累累啊
What can I say? The scene was a gold mine.
拜托  不是人人都找得到证据
Come on. Now we both know gold's only as good as the man digging.
好吧  什么时候你想来
Yeah, well, anytime you want to come back,
再看这些证物的话
take a look at this stuff...
不用了  谢谢  没必要
No, thanks. Don't need to.
你怎么不做笔记呢
You never took any notes.
我不用做笔记
I don't need to.
看来你在部队真是个神人啊
So you were some real hot shit in the Army, huh?
一般吧
I did all right.
军队警察到底负责什么工作  劝架吗
So what does an Army cop do mostly? Break up bar fights?
跟你做的工作差不多  只有一点小区别
I did what you do pretty much, with one minor difference.
是什么
What's that?
我面对的每一个罪犯都是训练有素的
Every suspect was a trained killer.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
你觉得他停车的时候为什么要投币缴费呢
Why do you think he paid for parking?
什么
Pardon?
他马上就要向一群陌生人连开六枪
He's about to fire six shots into a crowd of strangers.
还会担心被贴罚单吗
And he's worried about the meter maid?
他就是疯了  不行吗
"Simple loony" Won't do it for you?
我还是喜欢有其他的推论
I like to have at least one alternate theory.
习惯
Habit.
肌肉记忆
Muscle memory.
或者他根本没意识到他投币了
I don't think he knew he was doing it.
我说过  你们干得不错
Like I said, it's damn fine work.
大兵
Hey, Army.
枪上的序列号是多少
What's the serial number on the rifle?
你知道他用的那枚硬币是哪年的吗
What's the date on the quarter?
1968年
1968.
只见树木不见森林啊  探长
Forest for the trees, Detective.
只见树木不见森林
Forest for the trees.
我能坐这儿吗
Mind if I share your table?
桑迪  又有多沙的意思
我叫桑迪
I'm Sandy.
我也是  上周
So was I. Last week.
我去了佛罗里达州的海滩
On a beach, in Florida.
你叫什么
What's your name?
吉米・里斯
Jimmie Reese.
吉米不像是你的名字
You don't look like a Jimmie.
那我该叫什么
What do I look like?
不知道  反正不是吉米
I don't know. But not a Jimmie.
你是新来的吗
So you're new in town?
算是吧
Usually.
这有点吵
It's kind of loud in here.
想去个安静点的地方吗  我有车
Do you want to maybe go someplace quieter? I have a car.
你够开车的年龄吗
You're old enough to drive?
我到了可以做许多事的年龄
I'm old enough to do a lot of things.
我没有钱  桑迪
I'm on a budget, Sandy.
什么
What?
我没钱付你
I can't afford you.
我不是妓女
I'm not a hooker.
那我更养不起你了
Then I really can't afford you.
真的  我在汽车配件店工作
Seriously, I work at the auto parts store.
我的意思是
What I mean is,
人们都愿意找最便宜的女人
the cheapest woman tends to be the one you pay for.
我不是妓女
I am not a hooker!
也对  妓女都开得起玩笑的
No. A hooker would get the joke.
-发生什么事了  -他说我是妓女
-What's this? -He called me a whore.
是吗
Is that true?
我没说妓女  她自以为的  我说的是荡妇
Well, nobody said whore. She inferred hooker, but I meant slut.
她是我们的妹妹
Hey. That's our sister.
她接吻技术好吗
Is she a good kisser?
出来
Hey. Outside.
你先去付账吧
Pay your cheque first.
我一会再付
I'll pay later.
你一会儿就付不了了
You won't be able to.
是吗
You think?
当然  你要试试吗
All the time. You should try it.
真好笑  不过我要狠狠揍你一顿
It's a great joke, but I'm going to beat your ass.
你是想在这挨揍还是去外面
Do you want to do that here or outside?
出去
Outside.
留在这  桑迪
Stay here, Sandy.
我倒是想见血
I don't mind the sight of blood.
当然  见血说明你没怀孕
When it means you're not pregnant, anyway.
你现在还觉得好笑吗  讨厌鬼
You still think you're funny now, creep?
闭嘴  桑迪  没人跟你说话
Shut your mouth, Sandy! No one is talking to you.
现在跑还来得及
It's your last chance to walk away.
开玩笑吧  我们五对一
Are you kidding? It's five against one.
是三对一
It's three against one.
你不识数吗
How do you figure?
一旦我把领头的打倒  也就是你
Well, once I take out the leader, which is you,
还得再对付一两个热血的小跟班
I'll have to contend with one or two enthusiastic wingmen.
剩下的两个通常会逃命
The last two guys, they always run.
你以前干过吗
You've done this before?
是啊
Yeah.
不早了
It's getting late.
记住
Remember,
是你自找的
you wanted this.
没事  你没事
It's okay. You're okay.
起来
Get up.
好吧
Okay.
现在我们知道谁是谁了
Now we know who's who.
来吧
Let's get this done.
还来
Really?
妈的
Shit!
趴在地上
On the ground!
反应真神速啊  伙计们
That's a pretty impressive response time, fellas.
趴下
Do it!
手背后面
Hands behind your back.
谁指使你的
Who hired you?
我们走
Let's go.
你好  海伦
Hey, Helen.
我香水喷太多了吗
Am I wearing too much perfume?
是我闻得太仔细  爱默生探长
Breathing too sternly. Detective Emerson.
-有人死了吗  -如果有呢
-Somebody dead? -And if someone is?
那他们肯定是羞辱死的  我下手很轻了
Then they died of shame. 'Cause I was being gentle.
我大概明白你为什么要到处跑了  雷彻
I'm starting to understand why you move around a lot, Reacher.
这么说没有人死
So no one's dead.
有人可能没办法正常走路了
One guy likely won't ever walk right again.
-你想控告我  -非常想
-You want to charge me. -Very much.
但没有人提起诉讼
But no one's pressing.
可悲的是  没有
Sadly, no.
我可以走了吗
Am I free to go?
等一下  爱默生
Hey, Emerson.
4862681
4862681.
什么
What's that?
巴尔步枪的编号
It's the serial number on Barr's rifle.
你是为我工作的  明白吗
You're working for me, do you understand that?
你所做的一切都关系我的事务所
So everything you do is a reflection on my firm.
关系着我的名誉
On me.
我是被陷害的
I was set up.
你在跟律师说话
You're talking to a lawyer.
有个女孩  跟我搭讪  寻衅打架
There was this girl. She came onto me. Picked a fight.
酒吧里常有的事
Which never happens in a bar.
听到我的名字时她很吃惊
She was thrown when I told her my name.
她以为是迈克・泰森[重量级拳王]吗
She was expecting Mike Tyson?
她没预料到是吉米・里斯
She wasn't expecting Jimmie Reese.
洋基队的二垒手
Yankees second baseman.
你为什么说你是洋基队二垒手
Why did you say you were a Yankees second baseman?
我总是用洋基队二垒手的名字
I always use Yankees second basemen.
我并没说我就是洋基队二垒手
I didn't say I was a Yankees second baseman,
我只是说
I just said...
问题是
Look, the point is,
她希望听到的是杰克・雷彻
she was expecting to hear "Jack Reacher."
她知道我是谁
She knew who I was.
甚至还没开打  警察就出动了
And the cops were rolling before the fight even started.
那五个小子是她的哥哥  得了吧
And those five guys are her brothers? Come on.
有人派这些人来对付我
Someone sent those boys to put me down.
谁
Who?
如果说今天有人在河边跟踪你
If someone followed you at the river today,
那很可能是警察  而且我很怀疑
it was probably a cop. And I highly doubt...
有三件事警察永远不会做
There are three things cops never do.
凯迪拉克:知名豪华车品牌 象征权力和尊贵
他们不投票给民主党  不会开凯迪拉克
They don't vote Democrat, they don't drive Cadillacs,
不会开私车办公
and they never use personal vehicles.
那不是警察
It's not a cop.
可能是私人侦探  或者是地方检察官
A P.I., then, or the D.A.'s office.
你认为是你父亲的办公室陷害我吗
You think your father's office would set me up?
为什么有人会陷害你呢
Why would anyone set you up?
你今天怎么样
How was your day?
和你希望的一模一样
It went exactly the way I think you hoped it would.
你还好吧
You okay?
你了解到什么
What'd you learn?
克丽丝・法里奥22岁
Chrissie Farrior was 22.
是朋友家6岁女儿的保姆
A nanny caring for the six-year-old daughter of family friends.
她终于攒够了去中国旅行的钱
She'd finally saved enough money for a trip to China,
其实  她一周前就该走的
in fact, she should have left the week before.
但是她照看的女孩
But the girl she cared for
想让克丽丝留下来陪她过7岁生日
wanted Chrissie to stay for her 7th birthday.
她们那天是去市中心买派对礼服
They'd gone downtown that day to shop for a party dress.
丽塔・科罗纳多是十字河商业区的清洁工
Rita Coronado worked as a cleaning lady at the River Cross Plaza.
她经常工作迟到  但是有个很好的理由
She was usually late for work, but she had a good reason.
因为她的儿子马尔科9岁了
Since her son Marco was nine years old
她得亲自把他送到学校
she had to personally drop him at school
以确保他有去上学
to make sure he actually went.
她的付出终于有了回报
But her dedication had paid off.
马尔科成了荣誉生
Marco was now an honour student.
为了奖励他努力学习
As a reward for all his hard work,
丽塔打算带他看第一场棒球比赛
Rita was taking him to his first baseball game.
那天下午
And she was on her way
她正打算去取票
to pick up the tickets that very afternoon.
南希・霍尔特跟她丈夫说的最后一句话是个谎话
Nancy Holt's last words to her husband were a lie.
-我爱你  宝贝  再见  -再见
-I love you, babe. See you! -Bye.
她说她要去保养汽车
She told him she was taking her car to be serviced,
但实际上  她去了市中心
but in fact, she was headed downtown.
很完美
It's perfect.
她告诉店员
She told the clerk
她不想留下信用卡消费记录
she didn't want the purchase showing up on her credit card.
她想给丈夫一个十周年纪念日惊喜
She wanted to surprise her husband for their 10th anniversary
-还有几天就到了  -谢谢你
-just a few days away. -Thank you.
奥赖恩・阿彻一向不喜欢丈夫的建筑生意
Oline Archer never liked her husband's construction business,
即便是在帮助他成为
even after helping him
全国最大的承包商之一以后
become one of the largest contractors in the county.
所以当他疾病缠身
So it came as a relief
又面临昂贵的诉讼费用
when his failing health and a costly lawsuit
被迫要把生意卖给对手时  她感到欣慰
were forcing them to sell to the competition.
罗布
Rob?
救命啊  救命啊
Help! Help!
她的丈夫把生命献给了公司
Her husband had given his life for the company.
现在公司是她的了
But now that it was hers,
但她却不想卖掉
she couldn't bring herself to let it go.
她那天要去申请担保贷款
She was on her way to secure a loan that day
那样就可以继续经营她一直痛恨的生意
so she could keep the business she'd always hated.
达伦・索亚是一位投资经纪人
Darren Sawyer was an investment broker
和丽塔在同一栋楼工作
in the same building where Rita worked.
他的妻子说他回来的越来越晚
His wife said he'd grown increasingly distant of late.
她不记得他们的最后一句话是什么
She can't remember their last words to one another,
但当时并不愉快
but they weren't kind.
达伦尸体旁有一束玫瑰
Darren's body was found beside a fresh bouquet of roses
是他早上买的
he'd bought that morning
让她的妻子感到安慰的是
and his wife takes comfort in the fact that,
在他生命的最后一刻
in his last moments,
很可能就是在想她
he was most likely thinking of her.
我们会没事的  我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay. We're gonna be okay.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
我们会没事的  我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay, we're gonna be okay,
we're gonna be okay, we're gonna be okay.
你知道了什么
So what'd you learn?
你想让我承认你是对的
You want me to say you were right.
你想让我说这场官司没有异议
You want me to say that this isn't the fight.
詹姆斯・巴尔该死
James Barr should die.
也许死不足惜
Maybe he should.
我是说  你对受害者了解到了什么
I meant, what did you learn about the victims.
你还想听什么
What more do you want?
五个无辜的人被毫无原由地被谋杀了
They were five innocent people senselessly murdered.
抱歉  你能穿上衣服吗
I'm sorry. Could you please put a shirt on?
这就是我的衣服
This is my shirt.
你把行李弄丢了吗
You lose your luggage?
我没有行李
I don't have any luggage.
我刚才说到哪了
What was I saying?
五个无辜的人
Five innocent people.
毫无缘由地被杀了  对
Murdered at random, yes.
你知道这个国家每年会死多少人吗
You know how many people die in this country every year?
250万
Two and a half million.
这就意味着每一天
That means every day,
都平均有7000人死亡
roughly 7,000 average Americans wake up for the last time.
上周五  其中的五个人
Last Friday, five of them
死在了同一地点
converged on a single spot and died together.
这是偶然吗
Is that random?
你觉得是什么呢
What else would you call it?
比如说达伦和南希吧  他们可能有恋情
Well, take Darren and Nancy. Odds are they were having an affair.
你说什么
Excuse me?
人们不会在上班的路上给妻子买玫瑰的
You don't buy roses for your wife on the way to work.
而是在下班回家的时候买
You buy them on the way home.
还有纪念日就在周末
And you don't worry about a charge showing up on your credit card
你是不会介意信用卡的消费记录的
when your anniversary is that weekend.
除非你在掩藏这个礼物
Unless it's the gift you're hiding.
这就是为什么在别人都跑开的时候
And that's why she kept walking
她却继续走过去
while everyone else ran.
你怎么可以证明
You can't prove that.
有什么难的  手机  邮件
How hard would it be? Cell phones, e-mails.
只要有人愿意调查
All it takes is someone willing to dig.
你到底想说什么
What's your point exactly?
我的意思是
My point is that
有两个受害者严格来说并不是偶然的
two of the victims weren't there strictly by chance.
我需要巴尔朋友的名单
I need a list of Barr's known associates.
没有  他没有朋友
There isn't one. He didn't have any.
他是典型的独行者
He's a classic loner.
甚至都不跟邻居说话
He didn't even talk to his neighbours.
他是个安静的人  从不打扰别人
He was a quiet man. Never bothered anyone.
是啊
Yeah, exactly.
你有他的信用卡清单吗
You have his credit card statement?
可以弄到  为什么要
I can get it. Why?
我需要他所有的活动地点
I need the list of all the places he hung out.
酒吧  保龄球馆  脱衣舞俱乐部
Bars, bowling alleys, strip clubs,
射击场
gun ranges.
所有有人见过他的地方
Anywhere someone would remember him.
我们想要找什么呢
What do we hope to find?
我得睡觉了
I need some sleep.
你也是
You, too.
你不会以为我
You don't really think I'm gonna...
7点来接我
Be back to pick me up at 7:00.
好  没问题
Yep. Absolutely.
你和谁来的
Who's with you?
发生什么了
What happened?
是他  对吧
That's him, isn't it?
我没看到你
I ain't seeing you, man!
放松  发生什么了
Relax. What happened?
巴尔的律师雇了一个探员
Barr's attorney hired an investigator.
叫雷彻  是个高级军队调查员
Name of Reacher. Some sort of top-shelf Army cop.
他和巴尔曾同在巴格达
He was in Baghdad the same time as Barr.
然后呢
So?
巴尔点名要这个军人
So Barr asked for this soldier by name.
今天他出现在河边  然后去了高速路
Then he shows up at the river today. Then up on the highway.
看起来像是知道了什么
Almost like he knew something.
你说过我们不喜欢别人插手
And you said we don't like people asking questions.
对  当然不喜欢
No, we sure don't.
所以我采取了行动
So I took steps.
你采取了行动
You took steps.
本地人  我手下
Local people. My guys.
你搞砸了
And it blew back on you.
我以为五个人能搞定
I figured five guys would do it.
你要清楚你的权限
This franchise was yours to manage.
到此为止
That's all.
采取行动是我们的事  明白吗
Maintenance is our thing, you understand?
我明白  但是我联系不上你
Yeah, I understand. I couldn't reach you!
我们就是这样工作的
Well, that's how this works.
我不得不做个决定
Well, I had to make a decision!
我需要这几个本地人的名字
These locals, I want their names.
在文件里
It's in the file.
有人知道你的身份吗
Any of them know who you are?
只有一个  不过我打点好了
Just one, but I took care of it.
你
You...
-尸体在哪  -分尸了
-Where's the body? -It's distributed.
别这样  没人会发现的
Relax! No one's gonna find it.
要是我们想让别人发现呢
Suppose we want it found, yeah?
为什么
Why the hell would you want it found?
因为我们有自己的做事方式
'Cause we got a way of doing things so they stay done.
干净利落
Clean!
失踪一个人不叫干净利落
A missing person isn't clean.
老天啊  你只需要杀该死的一个人
Christ's sakes, man. You only had to kill one goddamn person.
却杀了五个  这也叫干净利落
You tapped five! You call that clean?
这叫不留痕迹
I call it done.
他们在调查枪手  而不是目标
They're looking at the shooter, not the target.
天啊
Jesus.
现在已经够乱了  以后就不会再乱了
We make it messy now so it won't get messy later.
我们不能留下任何问题
And we don't leave questions unanswered ever.
好  好吧  我会弥补
Okay, all right. Okay. I can fix this.
-睁开眼  -不  我没看到你
-Open your eyes. -No, I ain't seeing you!
现在无所谓了
It makes no difference now.
我做错了
I made a mistake.
我还有用  只要告诉我怎么弥补
I mean, you can still use me, just tell me how to fix...
想活命  就别说弥补
To survive. Don't say "Fix it,"
因为你弥补不了
Because you can't.
我们刚收拾完烂摊子  你就又搞砸了
We covered up the one mess. You made another.
好吧  你说得对
All right. You're right.
你说得对  对极了  对不起
You're right. You're absolutely right. I'm sorry.
告诉我该怎么做
Just tell me what I have to do.
西伯利亚位于俄罗斯北部 气候寒冷
我曾在西伯利亚坐牢
I was in prison in Siberia.
穿着死人的衣服过了第一个冬天
I spent my first winter wearing a dead man's coat.
口袋破了洞
A hole in one pocket.
我在手指冻烂之前
I chewed these fingers off
把它们咬了下来
before the frostbite could turn to gangrene.
这几个是为了逃避硫矿劳动咬掉的
These I gave up to avoid working in the sulphur mine.
很多人死了  而我就是这样活下来的
That is how I survived when so many others did not.
像这样难得的人一定会有所作为
A man this rare can always be of use.
给我看看  你有多难得
So show me. Show me you are rare.
让我看看你为了活下去能做什么
Show me you'll do anything to survive.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你左手手指
The fingers from your left hand.
你有  你有刀吗
Have you... Have you got a knife?
我在西伯利亚的时候有刀吗
Did I have a knife in Siberia?
别  拜托  别开玩笑了
No... Come on, you've got to be kidding.
你可以做到的
You can do it.
让我看看
Show me.
天啊
Christ!
不行  我不行
Can't! I can't.
还是选择吃枪子
Always the bullet.
真不明白
I don't understand.
那当兵的怎么办
What do we do about the soldier?
照老规矩办
What we always do.
巴尔的信用卡清单  目击者证词
Barr's credit card statement. Eyewitness testimonies.
咖啡  你要不加奶的  对吧
Coffee. You take it black, right?
我能怎么办  我只能在家里工作
Yeah. What can I say? I take my work home.
巴尔的信用卡清单恐怕是个死胡同
Afraid Barr's credit card statement's a dead end.
没有酒吧或脱衣舞俱乐部  什么也没有
No bars, no strip joints, nothing.
基本只是加油站和杂货店
Pretty much just gas and groceries.
我需要你查一下
I need you to look for gun ranges
距此100至150英里的射击场
between 100 and 150 miles from here.
只找射击距离在300码以上的
Limit your search to ranges longer than 300 yards.
可以  但得告诉我原因
Sure, if you tell me why.
巴尔每周六都去加油
Barr consistently filled his tank on Saturday,
周日又要加
and again on Sunday.
说明他几乎每周末都跑长途
He took a long drive almost every weekend.
-去哪都有可能  -是的
-He could be going anywhere. -Yes.
如果是去酒吧
And if it's bars,
保龄球馆  或脱衣舞俱乐部
bowling alleys or strip clubs,
我们肯定找不到
we'll never find it.
但是比赛级别的靶场呢  很可能有两个
But a Match-level gun range? There might be two.
并且他用的是自制子弹
And he made his own bullets.
说明他经常射击
That means he shot a lot.
我猜他每个周六都会去
I'm guessing every Saturday.
也许是和朋友一起
Maybe with a friend.
为什么找他的朋友这么重要
Why is it so important you talk to his friends?
前提是他有朋友
Assuming he had any.
我要在汽车配件店下车
Drop me at the auto parts store.
等等  哪一个
I... Wait. Which one?
不知道  她只说了汽车配件店
I don't know. She just said "The auto parts store."
她  她是谁
She? Who?
雷彻  能说的具体点吗
Reacher, can you be a little more specific?
我不是说哪一家汽车配件店
I didn't say "An auto parts store."
你第一个想到的配件店是哪家
Which one stands out in your mind as the auto parts store?
要我等你吗
You want me to wait?
不用  我晚点去办公室找你
No, I'll meet you back at the office later.
你怎么过去
How will you get there?
搭便车
I'll hitch a ride.
需要点什么
Can I help you?
桑迪在这工作吗
Sandy work here?
找她什么事
What's this about?
就是说她在  谢谢  我要跟她谈谈
So she does, thanks. I need to speak with her.
是私事
It's a personal matter.
-她正在工作  -法律上的私事
-She's on the clock. -Legal personal matter.
你是什么人  警察吗
What are you, a cop?
叫她出来  加里
Call her out, Gary.
-我要看你证件  -叫桑迪出来
-I'm gonna need to see some I.D. -Go get Sandy.
我要看你的证件
Well, I need to see something.
看看救护车怎么样
How about the inside of an ambulance?
好吧  我要报警
Okay, I'm calling the police.
我觉得桑迪不想警察掺和进来
I don't think Sandy wants the police involved
不然问她吧
but let's ask.
站住  你
Hey! You...
你好  我需要帮助  你站住
Hello? I need some help. Hello? Hey! You!
你不能进来
No. You are not allowed back in here, man!
该死
Shit.
你认识他吗
You know this guy?
告诉他
Tell him.
你先出去  加里
Give us a few, Gary.
听着  不是我  我不知道
Listen, I wasn't... I didn't know.
我不知道会这样
I didn't know that was going to happen!
是杰布
It was Jeb.
高个子的那个
The big guy.
杰布・奥利弗
Jeb Oliver.
他说你会吃这一套
He told me you were a predator.
以为你会上钩
You were supposed to start groping me.
别伤害我
Just don't hurt me.
桑迪  坐下
Sandy, sit down.
杰布在哪
Where can I find Jeb?
不知道  他今天没来上班
I don't know. He didn't come to work today.
这么说他也在这工作
So he works here.
是的
Yeah.
工作只是幌子  他制毒
It's bullshit, though. He cooks crystal.
给我他的地址
His address, write it down.
真的很抱歉  先生
I'm really sorry, mister.
我当时以为你是个变态
You were supposed to be a pervert.
而且这100块赚得容易
And it was an easy 100 bucks.
就这么点
That's all?
杰布说什么就得做什么
When Jeb asks, you do what he says.
我惹上麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
把你的车借我就没事了
Not if you lend me your car.
-我没有车  -你当然有  就在外面
-I don't have a car. -Well, sure you do. It's outside.
我猜是那辆卡玛洛
I'm guessing you're the Camaro.
那辆奇怪的小皮卡一看就是加里的
That whimsy little pickup has Gary written all over it.
钥匙呢
Keys?
我不能给你钥匙  那是杰布的车
I can't. It's Jeb's car!
我替他开回家给他个惊喜
Well, won't he be surprised when I drive it home for him.
你到底是什么人  先生
Who are you, mister?
说实话
Really?
我不过是个喜欢独来独往的人
I'm just a guy who wants to be left alone.
我6点下班
I get off work at six!
也许我们可以
Maybe we could...
桑迪  听着
Sandy, listen.
你是个好姑娘
Now, you seem like a sweet girl.
你很漂亮
You're pretty.
显然也很聪明
You're obviously sharp,
加里的工作都是你帮他做的
doing Gary's books for him.
你不必受这些家伙的利用
You don't have to let these guys use you.
我这样的女孩子还能怎么做
It's just what girls like me do.
你有钱吗
You got money?
有一点
A little.
出去躲一阵子
Get out of town for a couple of days.
为什么
Why?
离开这个镇子  桑迪
Get out of town, Sandy.
杰布在家吗
Is Jeb home?
我有房屋搜查令
I have a warrant to search the premises.
我明白了
I see.
如果你不介意的话
Well, if you don't mind...
揍他  揍他  揍他
Get him! Get him! Get him!
让我来
I got this!
好的  好的
Okay, okay.
好了
All right.
不许动
Don't move.
我帮你说吧
I'll tell you what.
只要我一动  你就会扣扳机
When I move, you pull the trigger.
-杰布在哪里  -他不在这儿
-Where's Jeb? -He's not here.
我在那里能找到他
Where can I find him?
上帝啊  我的手
Jesus! My hand!
你不该玩枪的  我在哪里能找到他
Well, you shouldn't play with guns. Where can I find him?
你开着他的车回来的  你告诉我
You're the one driving his car. You tell...
我最后见到他是从拘留所出来的时候
The last I saw him, we was all leaving jail.
他说他必须去见个人
He said he had to see a guy.
-什么人  -我不知道
-What guy? Who? -I don't know.
我不知道  我发誓
I don't know, I swear.
我只知道他妈妈吸多了
Next I know, his mom woke up from a bender
醒来的时候所有东西都不见了
and his shit's all gone.
他会这样不告而别吗
Is he the sort to light out like that?
不  不会  他从来不会丢下他的妈妈
No, no, man. He'd never leave his moms alone.
一定出事了
Shit ain't right.
-有车吗  -在外面
-Got a car? -It's outside.
钥匙
Keys.
我的手  兄弟  钥匙在我的口袋里
My hand, man. They're in my pock...
好的  好的
Okay, okay.
现在看看你的朋友们
Now look at your friends.
再看着我的脸
Now look at my face.
你还想再见到我么
Do you ever want to see me again?
绝不
No way.
我偷了你的车吗
Am I stealing your car?
你想用多久就用多久
Use it as long as you like.
你真是太好了
You're very kind.
我认为杰布・奥利弗已经死了
I think Jeb Oliver's dead.
-杰布・奥利弗是谁  -酒吧里的家伙
-Who's Jeb Oliver? -He was the guy from the bar.
上帝  你怎么对他下手那么重
Jesus, how hard did you hit him?
什么  不  不是我
What? No, not me.
不  他是被谋杀的
No, he was murdered.
而且有人试图制造出他离开镇子的假象
And someone tried to make it look like he left town.
也许他只是出去一下
Well, maybe he just left town.
你出去旅游带浴帘吗
You pack your shower curtain when you travel?
这就是你得出结论的依据吗
Is this what you base your conclusions on?
你的头怎么了
What is that on your head?
你还是不知道的好
You don't want to know.
你在电话里说你有了新发现
You said on the phone you wanted to submit your findings.
詹姆斯・巴尔是个狙击手
James Barr was a sniper.
既不是最好的  也不是最差的
Not the best, not the worst.
但是他不间断地训练了两年
But he trained non-stop for two years.
这样训练目的何在
What does training like that do?
一般的训练能起到什么作用呢
What does any training do?
技巧变成了本能反应  肌肉记忆
Skills become reflex. Muscle memory.
射击时不假思索
You do without thinking.
同时通过灌输一些战术意识
It also makes people who aren't necessarily smart seem smart
使一个并不聪明的人看上去很聪明
by beating some tactical awareness into them.
现在  几乎所有你父亲在巴格达找到的
Now, 99% of the evidence your father has against Barr
对巴尔不利的证据都不能成立了
didn't exist in Baghdad,
并非巴尔聪明  而是因为他受过训练
not because Barr was smart, but because he was trained.
在那个停车场  太阳会晃到枪手的眼睛
See, from that garage, the shooter had the sun in his eyes.
目标左右移动
Targets were moving left and right.
对于任何狙击手来说射击环境都很恶劣
It's difficult conditions for any sniper.
但是巴尔在巴格达杀人时就在停车场
But Baghdad, you said Barr was in a parking garage then.
因为那次太阳当时在他的背后
Because in Baghdad, the sun's behind him.
目标向着他直线走来  排成一列纵队
Targets coming straight ahead, single file.
即使对中等水平的射手射击环境也很理想
Ideal conditions for even an average shooter
如果想营造同等环境
and the exact same conditions
他会把狙击点选在高速路桥上
he would've had up on that highway bridge.
在那里  他甚至都不需要下车
Up there, he would never even have to get out of the van.
没有停车计时器
No parking meter.
没有监控摄像头
No camera.
不会留下任何蛛丝马迹  逃脱毫无问题
No trace evidence left behind. And his escape is assured.
当然  我不是说他没有杀死河边那些人
Now, I'm not saying that he couldn't have killed
但是他不该这么杀
those people at the river, but he wouldn't have.
不应该用那种方法
Not that way.
-你的意思是他疯了  -不
-So you're saying he's crazy. -No.
你到底想说明什么呢
Well, what exactly are you saying?
如果只是单一的证据证明不了什么
Any single piece of evidence I'd buy.
但是所有的证据加起来的话
But all of it?
纤维  指纹  遗留的弹壳  我是说
Fibres, fingerprints, stray brass, I mean...
他竟然还付了停车费
And who the hell pays for parking?
不管他的神智是清醒还是疯狂都说不通
Sane or crazy, that just doesn't make sense.
好吧  所以巴尔他想被捕
Okay. So Barr, he wanted
而且他想要你来逮捕他
to get caught and he wanted you to catch him.
那也不能解释巴尔这样一个中等水平射手
That would not explain how Barr,
如何在恶劣的射击环境下能做到弹无虚发
an average shooter firing in poor conditions, never missed.
他有失手
He did miss.
确实有
He did.
一颗完整的子弹
A pristine bullet,
正巧留在了液体里
conveniently trapped by a liquid backstop.
正是这颗子弹把巴尔的枪和谋杀联系起来
The same bullet that tied Barr's gun to the killings.
可以说是控方唯一的
And arguably the prosecution's
也是最重要的一件证物
single most important piece of evidence.
如果巴尔想被逮捕  他做到了
If Barr wanted to get caught, he didn't miss.
不管是哪种情况  都说不通
Either way, it doesn't make sense.
如果他想逍遥法外  他很容易做到
If he wanted to get away with it, he likely would have
而如果巴尔想被逮捕
and if he wanted to get caught,
他没有能力做到这么完美
Barr was incapable of such perfection.
或许他只是运气好  6发全中
Or maybe he just got lucky, six shots out of six.
本来我也想接受这种观点
That's what I was willing to accept,
然而那些家伙来找我麻烦
then those guys took a run at me.
不管派他们来的人是谁  他犯了个错误
Whoever sent them made a mistake.
那不过是寻常的酒吧斗殴而已
It was just a bar fight.
也许吧
Maybe.
也许是有人紧张了  想让我离开
Or maybe someone got nervous, tried to run me off.
或者让我不省人事  成为下一个替罪羊
Or put me in a coma, right next to their patsy.
替罪羊
Patsy?
这是个巨大的阴谋
It was such a great crime scene.
没有人想到这一点因为它太完美了
No one stopped to think it might be too great.
爱默生想不到
Not Emerson.
你的父亲也想不到
Not your father.
甚至连巴尔的辩护律师也想不到
Not even Barr's own defence attorney.
但是巴尔知道我会想到的
But Barr knew I would,
无论我多么希望这就是事实
no matter how much I wanted it to be true.
这就是他向我求助的原因
That's why he asked for me.
等等
Wait.
你是说
Are you suggesting...
詹姆斯・巴尔是无辜的
James Barr is innocent.
你已经想明白了整件事  是吗
You can see what this is, can't you?
你得到一个案子
You've got a case in your hands
这也许是你接到的最后一个案子
that may be the last case you'll ever have
为了不搞砸它  你会不择手段
and you'll do anything not to hit the bottom of it.
海伦
Helen.
知道吗  你真不该退休的
You know, you never should have retired.
听着
Just, look. Listen.
据我所知
For all I know, you were standing at an intersection
三天前你还是个无业游民
with a cardboard sign three days ago.
我雇了你  上帝  我父亲说得对
And I hired you. Jesus, my father was right.
-海伦  海伦  -现在完全说得通了
-Helen. Helen. -It makes total sense now.
这就是你的生存之道  四海为家
It's the way you live, the way you move around.
你与现实世界格格不入  不是吗
You're just not cut out for the real world, are you?
你是不是害怕自己也会步巴尔的后尘
Are you afraid you'll end up like Barr?
-海伦  -这才是事实真相吧
-Helen. -Is that what this is?
看看窗外
Look out the window.
不  我还有工作要做
No, I have work to do.
-你必须离开了  -就迁就我一下吧
-And you need to leave. -Just humour me. Okay.
放开我
Let go of me.
告诉我你看到了什么
Would you tell me what you see?
我每天看到的都一样
I see the same things I see every day.
想象一下你从未见过这景色
Well, imagine you've never seen it.
想象你的一生都在世界的其他地方度过
Imagine you've spent your whole life in other parts of the world
每天都被告知你在捍卫自由
being told every day you're defending freedom.
最终你觉得你受够了
And finally you decide you've had enough.
是时候睁开眼睛看看
Time to see
你奉献自己的一生所追求的是什么
what you've given up your whole life for.
也许你该为自己争取些自由
Maybe get some of that freedom for yourself.
看看这些人
Look at the people.
告诉我他们自由吗
Now tell me which ones are free.
远离债务
Free from debt.
焦虑
Anxiety.
压力
Stress.
恐惧
Fear.
失败  侮辱  背叛
Failure. Indignity. Betrayal.
现在有多少人还记得他们儿时的愿望
How many wish they were born knowing what they know now?
扪心自问  如果给他们重来一次的机会
Ask yourself how many would do things
有多少人会做出同样的选择
the same way all over again?
他们中有多少人会选择过我这样的生活
And how many would live their lives like me?
现在看着街对面那辆银色的奥迪
Now look at the silver Audi across the street,
它已经跟了我整整一天了
the one that's been following me all day.
这能证明什么呢
What does that prove?
这是它的车牌号  追查需要多久
Here's the tag number. How long would it take you to run it?
夜里这时候  我不知道  1个小时吧
At this time of night? I don't know. An hour?
查一下
Do it.
查到了我就离开
Do it, and then I'll leave.
什么时候
When?
不  这个问题交给我  我来处理
No, this is my problem now. I'll handle it.
你好
Yeah?
你的身份暴露了
You're blown.
那个律师在追查你的车牌
The lawyer's running the licence plates.
好的  要动手吗
Yeah. So do it?
知道了
Done.
去这个地址
Go to this address.
好吧  让我们假设巴尔没有杀人
All right, let's just say that Barr didn't do it.
或者是受人唆使去杀人的
Or did it 'cause someone put him up to it.
不管是哪一种  为什么要这么做
Either way, what have you got?
阴谋
Conspiracy.
好吧  预谋杀死5个毫不相关的人
Yeah, conspiracy to kill five random people?
没有动机
There's no motive.
-很奇怪  对吗  -可笑的阴谋论
-It's ridiculous, right? -It's grassy knoll ludicrous.
继续查下去毫无意义
No point looking any further.
完全正确
Exactly.
这是什么
What's this?
动机  好好地抓住它
The motive. Just hold onto it.
我们在玩什么  线索游戏
What are we playing, Clue?
你好
Yeah?
你说吧
Give it to me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你确定那辆车跟了你一整天了吗
You sure that car was following you all day?
从你开车来接我开始  怎么了
As soon as you picked me up. Why?
它是乐班德尔公司名下的
It's registered to a company called Lebendauer Enterprises.
一场杀死5个毫不相关的人的阴谋
A conspiracy to kill five random people?
这太奇怪了
That's ridiculous.
四个
Four.
用四个毫不相关的人
Four random people.
来掩饰一个特定的目标
To hide one specific target.
有人想得到奥赖恩・阿彻的建筑生意
Someone needed Oline Archer's construction business.
而奥赖恩不愿意放手
And Oline wouldn't let it go.
这是一个具有说服力的推论
It's a convincing theory.
但也仅仅是个推论
But it's just a theory.
第一枪的精准度是最差的
The first round is the least accurate.
狙击手称之为冷弹
The snipers call it a cold shot.
同时  你的目击证人描述说
Meanwhile, your eyewitness described a pause
在第一和第二枪之间有一个停顿
between the first and second rounds.
这一枪杀手不慌不忙
The one shot where the killer took his time.
奥赖恩・阿彻是第二个受害者
And Oline Archer was the second victim.
关键的一枪
The one shot that mattered.
但这仅仅是个推论
But it's just a theory.
这个陷阱是专为巴尔设计的
This frame was custom made for Barr.
设计者知道发生在巴格达的事
Whoever chose him knew about Baghdad
而唯一能够告诉他这一切的
and the only one who could have told him about Baghdad
就是巴尔自己
was Barr himself.
他至少有一个朋友  一个密友
He has at least one friend. A very close one.
找到这个朋友  你就找到了真正的枪手
Now, you find that friend, you'll find the real shooter.
找到真正的枪手  雷彻
Find the real shooter? Reacher,
我的工作是向陪审团提出合理的疑点
my job is to present the jury with reasonable doubt.
到此为止
Period.
如果我们抓住犯案的真凶呢
What about catching the guys who really did this?
-抓住真凶吗  -将他们绳之以法呢
-Catching the guys who did this? -Bringing them to justice?
不  我不能把这些提交给法庭
No, I can't take this to court.
揭露事实真相
Exposing the truth.
即使我相信巴尔是无辜的也不行
Even if I believed Barr is innocent,
这不是我的工作
it's not my job.
我只是个律师  我不是警察
I am just a lawyer. I'm not a cop.
而且坦白地说  你也不是
And frankly, neither are you.
这件事我帮不上忙
I can't do this any more.
谢谢你的咖啡  律师
Thanks for the coffee, counsellor.
桑迪吗
Sandy?
等等  你是桑迪吧
Wait, it is Sandy, isn't it?
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
查理  我是杰布的朋友
Charlie. Jeb's friend?
得了  不要让我伤心了
Oh, come on, don't break my heart.
对不起  我不记得了
I'm sorry, I don't remember.
我们当时都嗑了药  昏昏沉沉的
Well, we were both pretty wasted.
是的
Yeah.
-怎么  你住在这里吗  -就在那里
-What, you live here? -Just up there.
不是吧
No shit.
我刚刚搬到后面来  真是太巧了
I just moved in around the back! How crazy is that?
真是好极了
It's wild.
是啊
Yeah.
你真漂亮
Wow! You look great.
谢谢
Thanks.
你看  我不想耽误你的时间
Well, look, you know, I don't want to keep you, so...
也许我们可以找个时间一起喝一杯
Maybe we can grab a drink sometime.
也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
今晚如何
Hey, how about tonight?
我已经有约了
I'm meeting some people.
好吧  那下次再说吧
Okay. Well, some other time, then.
下次再说
Some other time.
动手
Do it here.
什么
What?
雷彻
Reacher!
在俄亥俄有一个靶场
There's a gun range in Ohio,
标靶距离超过700码
targets out to 700 yards.
是唯一符合你要求的靶场
The only range that matches your requirements.
你应该去睡觉
You should sleep.
明天还要赶路呢
You have a long drive tomorrow,
我要去市政厅调阅奥赖恩的司法档案
and I need to go to city hall and pull up Oline's legal history.
我建议你别这么做  至少在我回来之前
I wouldn't do that. Not till I get back.
如果我没猜错的话  他杀死四个不相关的人
If I'm right, someone killed four random people
是为了不想让人直接调查奥赖恩
so no one would look directly at Oline.
如果我猜对了
And if I'm right,
你只要提到她的名字就会被杀
just saying her name could get you killed.
-你是说我应该害怕吗  -你聪明吗
-You saying I should be scared? -Well, are you smart?
显而易见
Obviously.
那么别害怕
Then don't be scared.
你要找谁
What exactly am I looking for?
能一拳就杀了那个姑娘的人
Someone who could kill that girl with one punch.
你要找的人住1109房
Oh, you want the guy in 1109.
厄尼・约翰逊
Ernie Johnson.
见到你就明白了
You'll see.
下车
Out of the car!
那个人是嫌疑犯  快点  跟上
That's our suspect! Move, move!
嫌疑犯在65号高速公路上向北行驶
Suspect is headed north on State Route 65.
我需要地面和空中支援
I need backup and air support.
举起手来
Hold up!
安全
All clear!
上帝啊  我简直不敢相信  不敢相信
Oh, God, I just don't believe it. I don't believe it!
一个小时前我申请了逮捕令
I issued the warrant an hour ago.
通过受害者的老板我们了解到
According to the victim's boss,
雷彻今早去过受害人工作的地方
Reacher was seen at her place of work this morning.
他还在那儿威胁过受害者的老板
Where he threatened her boss.
他今晚开的车
The car he was driving
是杰布・奥利弗一个朋友的
tonight belonged to a friend of Jeb Oliver's.
他打了那个人
The man he assaulted.
不  是那些人袭击了雷彻
No, those guys assaulted Reacher.
雷彻今天下午开着杰布・奥利弗的车
Reacher put three more men in the hospital
去了杰布・奥利弗家里
this afternoon at Jeb Oliver's place.
之后把三个人送进医院
After arriving in Jeb Oliver's car.
而且他离开医院之后杰布就失踪了
And Jeb hasn't been seen since he left the hospital.
海伦  如果你知道雷彻在哪里
Helen, if you know where Reacher is,
你必须告诉我们
you need to tell us.
我不知道他在哪里  几个小时之前
I don't know where he is. I have not seen him
他离开我的办公室  之后我再没见过他
since he left my office a few hours ago.
我觉得她说的是实话
I think she's telling the truth.
你觉得  爸爸  去你的
You think, Dad? Fuck you!
我告诉过你不要接近他
Hey, I told you not to go near him.
你们冲进我家还把我当成胁从犯来对待
You come into my home and you treat me like I'm an accessory!
-拜托  -好吧  得了  别吵了
-Please! You know... -All right. All right. Come on. Enough.
-让我来处理  -我还没问完呢
-Look, let me handle it. -I'm not done.
问话时间结束  给我出去
You're both done. Just get out.
我是海伦
This is Helen.
-我猜警察现在就在你那儿  -是的
-I'm guessing the police are there? -Yep.
看你的反应我猜在你把电话交给他们前
By your response I'm guessing I have about 30 seconds
我只有大概30秒的时间
before you hand them the phone.
如果是那样的话
If that.
如果你相信有人能陷害巴尔
If you believe someone could frame Barr,
你得相信他们同样也可以陷害我
you have to believe they could do the same to me.
我相信这很有可能
I suppose that's possible.
她是个可爱的孩子  海伦
She was a sweet kid, Helen.
因为我的原因他们杀了她
And they killed her because of me.
他们想让我离开
They want me to run.
但是我不会这么做
But I won't.
我要查完这件案子
I'm going to finish this.
这可不是个好主意
No, that's not a good idea.
听着
Listen.
两件事  第一
Two things. One, I...
我偷了你的车
I stole your car.
如果你想撇清关系
If you want to end this,
只要打个电话报失车辆就行了
just hang up the phone and report it missing.
我能理解
And I'll understand.
还有呢
And anything else?
如果我早点告诉你或许还有转机
I thought I'd be pushing it if I mentioned this earlier.
现在说也于事无补
Now I guess all bets are off.
你回想一下对爱默生和你父亲都说了什么
You need to watch what you say to Emerson and your father.
我认为他们之中的一个与案件有牵连
I think one of them is in on it.
好的  谢谢你打来电话  我得挂了
All right. Thanks for calling. I have to go.
等等  我从第一天起就被人跟踪
Wait. I've been followed from day one.
只有三个人知道我在这儿
Only three people knew I was here.
爱默生  你的父亲和你
Emerson, your father and you.
扪心自问  如果我们为巴尔洗脱罪名
You need to ask yourself,
谁的损失最大
who has the most to lose if we clear Barr?
谁曾经告诫你要离我远点
Who tried to warn you off me?
当然  也可能是我错了
Of course, I could be wrong. If you think I am,
如果你也这样认为  把电话交给警察
just hand over the phone.
你没有必要牵扯进来
There's no sense getting any deeper.
你在和谁通电话
Who's that you're talking to?
办公室
The office.
你们问完了吗
Are we done?
海伦  听着
Helen, listen.
-我们得  -晚安
-We need to... -Good night.
你这里有不少优秀的射手
You got some fine shooters here.
他们就像绝世美女
Fine as frog's hair.
十分稀有
Rarer, too.
因为打靶场里很多人连一环都打不中
'Cause most of them fellas out there can't shoot worth a damn.
你要他们三枪都射中黑环
You ask them to put three rounds in the black, well,
根本不可能
they'll suck it.
我想找这个靶场的主人
I'm looking for the owner.
我就是  我叫马丁・凯希
That'd be me. Martin Cash.
艾伦・沃德
Aaron Ward.
有什么能为你效劳吗  沃德先生
What can I do you for, Mr Ward? Ward?
我在找一个朋友
Yeah. I'm looking for a friend of mine.
我们曾一起在伊拉克服役
We served in Iraq.
他这个人很不受人待见  你明白吗
The guy just dropped off the grid, you know?
-我明白  是的  -是啊  是啊
-It happens. Yep. -Yeah. Yeah.
总之  他是个射手
Anyway, he was a shooter.
最近我听说  他住在这里附近
Last I heard, he lived around here somewhere and I...
他什么时候退役的
When did he get out of the Army?
我可没说是在军队
Well, I didn't say the Army.
你说你和他一起服役  你又没留锅盖头
Well, you said you served with him. You're no jarhead.
"锅盖头"是对美国海军陆战队士兵的谐称
明眼人都看得出来
Man on a flying horse could see that.
我爸爸参过军  这算不算
Well, my father was in the Corps, if that helps.
那你只能算半个男人
Well, that makes you half human.
你朋友叫什么名字
Your friend got a name?
詹姆斯・巴尔
Yeah. James Barr.
James Barr.
从来没有听说过这个人
Never heard of him.
我认为你见过
I think you have.
警察进来追问他的时候
I think you've been dreading
你肯定怕得要死吧
the moment some cop comes in here asking after him.
因为这附近的某个足球妈妈
Because it's for sure some soccer mom around here
足球妈妈:非常重视子女的妈妈  这里代指警察
肯定更担心你的射击场
is more worried about your range
而不是她后院的游泳池
than she is about the pool in her backyard
或者水槽下的疏通器
or the drain cleaner under her sink.
她才不管巴尔能否在100英里外击中
Wouldn't matter to her if Barr did his killing 100 miles away,
只要他来这里练习过
only that he came here to rehearse.
她随便就能找个理由把这儿关了
She'd have a case to shut you down
而你只能束手无策
and nothing better to do.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我想知道巴尔的朋友是谁
I want to know who Barr's friends were.
那些来这里练手的哥们
Those boys out there,
对涉及到他们利益的事都特别敏感
they're mighty touchy when it comes to their constitutional rights.
假如我告诉他们
Suppose I tell them
有个警察在这问我会员的事  会有什么结果
a cop is in here asking after my members?
-我不是警察  -那你是什么人
-I'm not a cop. -What are you?
我替巴尔的律师工作
I work for Barr's attorney.
我们有理由相信他是无辜的
We have reason to believe he's innocent.
你就胡扯吧
The hell you say.
你爱信不信
Be that as it may
我是唯一一个愿意找到这儿来的人
I'm the only one who's bothered to track him this far.
你帮我一把  我就欠你一个人情
You help me out, I'll be in your debt.
我要是不帮呢
And if I don't?
那就等着警察来找你吧
Maybe you can coach soccer.
你击中三次靶心再说吧
You put three in the centre and maybe we'll talk.
我能练练手吗
Can I have a few to warm up?
偏了六英寸
Six inches right.
沃德先生  你水平就这样吗  好好打
That's your mulligan, Mr Ward. Play ball!
开始吧
Let's go.
你有点生疏了 雷彻先生
You're a little rusty, Mr Reacher.
我在温布尔登杯上看到过雷彻先生射击
I saw a man by that name shoot for the Wimbledon Cup,
大概是十年前
what, ten years ago.
我也非常肯定你从来没当过洋基队的第二球手
And I'm pretty sure you never played second base for the Yankees
在1925年的时候
in 1925.
好了
Now,
我可以回答一个问题
I'll answer one question.
你这里射击最好的是谁
Who's your best shooter?
詹姆斯・巴尔
James Barr.
我一听说枪击案就把这些都摘下来了
I pulled all these down as soon as I heard about the shooting.
这是我这辈子见过枪法最好的
That's the best shot I ever seen this side of civilian life.
要是我说巴尔
Suppose I told you Barr
在服役时的最佳水平也打不到这样呢
wasn't this good on his best day in the Army.
靶子都是我亲手挂上去的
I handed out those targets myself.
这是我给每个人做的记号
That's my scrawl on every one.
你是按射向挂上去的吗
Do you hang them downrange, too?
你开玩笑吧
What, are you serious?
我是说很有可能巴尔有位朋友
I'm saying it's possible that Barr had a friend.
他在射击场上调换了靶子
One who switched the targets on the range.
也许还是巴尔允许的
Maybe Barr let him.
也许他觉得把名字挂到你的墙上很了不起
Made him feel like King Shit having his name up on your wall.
我从没见过任何一位枪手
I never saw one real shooter
甚至愿意跟他妈妈换靶的
who would do that for his own mother.
除非他想要陷害他妈妈犯了多宗谋杀
Unless he was framing his mother for multiple murder
并且利用你的射击场达到这一点
and using your range to do it.
巴尔不是一个人来的  对吗
Barr didn't come alone, did he?
这些疯子可能会杀了你
You know, one of these nuts is likely to kill you,
要是他们发现你装了监控器
they find that camera, there.
靠  我装监控器
Hell, the camera's there
就是怕哪个疯子要杀我
'cause one of these nuts is likely to kill me.
那就是巴尔
There's Barr.
我一直很喜欢他  一直很喜欢
I always liked him. Always liked him.
停
There.
就是他
Him.
那个狗崽子
That son of a bitch.
我是海伦・罗丁
Helen Rodin speaking.
找到了枪杀案的嫌疑人
Got a candidate for our shooter.
有录像  可能有指纹
Picture, possible prints
还有一位讨厌的目击者
and one pissed-off eyewitness.
我现在不方便讲话
I can't talk right now.
给我三个小时  等我回来
Just give me three hours to get back.
我到之前不要见任何人
And don't talk to anyone until I get there.
我会等的  谢谢
I'll look into that, thanks.
这是我今天早上能找到的
This is just what I could pull this morning.
税务记录  市级和州级许可证申请  投标合同
Tax records, city and state permit applications, contract bids.
乔治亚州的空壳公司
Shell corporation in Georgia.
这个是在俄国之后  而不是佛罗里达州
That's the one next to Russia, not Florida.
他们每次只在一个城市做事
They work one city at a time,
引起人们对当地建筑的关注
acquiring a local construction concern
刚好是在大型项目重建前夕
just ahead of major civic redevelopment.
他们建造毫无用处的桥  毫无用处的公路
They build bridges no one needs. Highways no one uses.
他们就像是癌症  一个不停生长的细胞
They're like a cancer. A cell that won't stop growing.
15年间他们换了12个地方
They moved 12 times in 15 years.
亚特兰大  阿尔伯克基
Atlanta, Albuquerque,
奥斯丁市  俄克拉荷马市  萨克拉门托
Austin, Oklahoma City, Sacramento.
总是被指控贪污
Always amidst allegations of corruption
包括数百万美元公款的失踪
including millions of dollars in missing public funds.
但是从来没遭受过调查  连传讯都没有
And yet never an investigation. Never even an inquiry.
乐班德尔公司就像是无疵可寻
It's as if Lebendauer Enterprises were above reproach.
可能这是因为
Well, maybe that's because
对他们的控告都来自竞争对手
the allegations come from the competition.
竞标失败了  心里不舒服
Outbid. Bitter.
比如说奥赖恩・阿彻
Like Oline Archer.
也可能是乐班德尔买通了一些重要官员呢
Or maybe Lebendauer has the cooperation of key officials.
也许买通的这些还不管用
And maybe when that cooperation isn't enough,
所以就杀了收买不到的人  比如奥赖恩・阿彻
they kill people who won't be bought off. Like Oline Archer.
海伦  这些东西你真的相信吗
Helen, how much of this do you honestly believe?
我信不信不重要
It doesn't matter how much I believe.
甚至我能不能证实也不重要
It doesn't even matter how much I can prove.
唯一重要的是有多少是真的
It only matters how much is true.
你知道自己听起来有多可笑吗
Do you know how delusional you sound?
你怎么回事
What happened to you?
你就这么想要这个人死掉
Are you really so set on putting this man to death
甚至不顾
that you'd ignore...
我以自己的名义找了这些资料
I pulled all of this paper under my own name.
如果杰克・雷彻是对的
If Jack Reacher's right,
我的性命  你女儿的性命
my life, your daughter's life,
现在岌岌可危
is in danger now.
我的命运全由你决定
Whatever happens to me next is on your head,
无论是不是与你有关
whether you're involved or not.
你是地区检察官
You are the District Attorney
我也向你提供了有力证据
and I've given you compelling evidence
来调查乐班德尔公司
to investigate Lebendauer Enterprises.
你的下一步会告诉我你到底站在哪边
Your next move will tell me which side you're on.
我明白了  这是个考验
I see. It's a test.
你可能很难相信  不过我是爱你的
Well, this may be hard for you to believe, but I do love you.
很显然我也不能置之不理
And obviously I'm not going to turn a blind eye,
尽管我觉得这简直荒唐透顶
no matter how absurd I find all of this.
所以  如果你真的觉得自己受到了威胁
So, if you really believe that you're in danger,
如果你真这么想的话
if you believe that,
那我的下一步
then the next order of business,
就是立刻将你保护性拘留
is to put you in protective custody right now.
如果你真的被收买了  我又能有多安全
And how safe will I be if you're part of it?
天哪  海伦
Jesus, Helen.
开会吗  还是私事
Business meeting or personal?
两者都有
Hard to tell them apart.
我想也是
I'll bet.
海伦吗
Helen?
不是
No.
对不起打错了
Sorry, wrong number.
你是雷彻吗
Is this Reacher?
你是谁
Who is this?
你是雷彻吗
Is this Reacher?
是你  跟踪我的那个人
It's you. The guy from the car.
你男朋友打来的
It's your boyfriend.
雷彻  是你吗
Reacher, is it you?
海伦  你受伤了吗
Helen, are you hurt?
如果你不在一小时内过来的话她就会受伤
Well, she's gonna be if you're not here in one hour.
要我告诉你怎么做吗
Do I have to tell you how this works?
你们会让我绕几圈确认没人跟着
You'll bounce me around to make sure I'm not followed,
然后走进你们的陷阱再杀了我
then walk me into an ambush and kill me.
你把惊喜都毁了
Aw, you ruined my surprise.
我有个更好的办法
Well, I can do one better.
我去了亨吉溪镇的射击场
I went down to the gun range at Hinge Creek.
我拿到了录像  指纹
I got the picture, prints,
我会去找联邦政府的人
and I'm going to the Feds.
那个律师随你处置
The lawyer's all yours.
把柴克找来
Get the Zec.
我又想了一下  还是把你杀了好
On second thought, I'd like to kill you.
那我们就胜者全得吧
Let's say winner take all.
听着  臭小子
Listen to me, you prick.
如果你一小时之内不来的话我就把这个婊子杀
I will kill this bitch if you're not here in one...
妈的
Shit!
你以为我是个英雄吗
You think I'm a hero?
我不是英雄  我是个一无所有的流浪者
I am not a hero. I'm a drifter with nothing to lose.
如果你杀了那姑娘来陷害我
You killed that girl to put me in a frame.
我扒光你的皮
I mean to beat you to death and drink your blood from a boot.
听着  按我说的做
Now, this is how it's going to work.
你把地址给我
You're gonna give me the address
我他妈什么时候准备好了就过来
and I'll be along when I am damn good and ready.
如果我打过来不是她接的
If she doesn't answer the phone when I call this number,
只要我觉得她受伤了
if I even think you've hurt her,
我会立刻消失
I disappear.
如果你够聪明的话  我不是威胁你
And if you're smart, that scares you,
你们在明我在暗
because I'm in your blind spot
而且我没什么别的可做
and I have nothing better to do.
你有笔吗
You got a pen?
不需要
Don't need one.
要是每次被大兵找来帮忙
If I had a dollar for every
我都收一美元就好了
time the Army called the Corps for help.
-给我带家伙了吗  -带了
-You have something for me? -Yeah.
给你
Here.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding, right?
我十年前看过你射击
Just because I saw you shoot ten years ago
并不代表我就允许你用我的枪杀人
doesn't mean I'll let you kill some asshole with my gun.
我说了这事很严重
I told you how serious this was.
我也来了  对吧
And I showed up, didn't I?
那就开始吧
So let's get to it.
你的对手应该
Now, your shooter will be
就在这些灯后  明白吗
right up there behind those lights. Okay?
他能看到来去两边的所有情况
He can cover both roads coming and going.
你一站起来就能将你击中
And kill you just as soon as you stand up.
那你能把他引出来吗
Well, can you take him out?
共进晚餐吗
What, to dinner you mean?
听着  我不知道你平时
Look, I don't know the type
都跟什么人打交道  雷彻
of people you normally associate with, Reacher.
不过我不习惯
But I'm not in the habit of
你一声令下就开车到郊外
driving out to the boonies at the drop of a hat
然后随便放倒一些陌生人好吗
and just picking off some total strangers, all right?
总之  我什么都看不到
Anyway, I can't see anything,
这些灯亮着就看不到
not with them lights up.
那把它们打灭
So shoot them out.
当然好  这样他们就知道我的位置了
Yeah, sure. And then he knows right where I am.
我还不如引火自焚呢
I might as well set myself on fire.
不对  先生  他们开枪了我再开枪
No, sir. I'll start shooting when he does.
那你说怎么让他们先开枪
And how do you propose we get him started?
你可以开跑啊
Well, you could always start running.
你眼睛怎么了
What's wrong with your eye?
我在保留夜视能力
I'm saving my night vision.
神枪手  你介不介意我问你个私人问题
Hey, Gunny, you mind if I ask you kind of a personal question?
怎么  你觉得我不会射击了吗
What, you don't think I can shoot any more?
这技能不练就没了
It is a perishable skill.
对  没错
Yeah, well,
还有一小时太阳就出来了
the sun will be up in an hour.
我们动手吧
Let's get going.
我听到他们管你叫柴克
I heard them call you the Zec.
意思是囚犯
That means "Prisoner."
对吗
Yes?
告诉我  你杀了这么多人
Tell me, killing all those people,
我只能认为你挣的钱
I have to believe the money you're making
不可能足够
can't possibly be enough to just...
足够
Enough?
对我来说没这回事
There is no such thing.
能拿的我们都会拿走
We take what can be taken.
这是我们的本职
This is what we do.
那你呢
And you?
这人这么做我能理解  但是你呢
This one I think I understand, but you?
你为什么这么做
Why'd you do it?
你说的好像我能有选择一样
You make it sound like I had a choice.
难道没有吗
Oh, didn't you?
你会明白的
You'll see.
你应该知道我已经采取了行动
You should know I've taken steps,
如果发生了任何事
that if anything happens...
如果你发生什么事
If anything happens to you,
那也是在你父亲眼前
it will happen in front of your father
他会求我手下留情
while he begs for your life.
你不该把他也搅进来
You should never have involved him.
现在你必须得说服他忘了这事  为了你
Now you will have to convince him to forget, for your sake
也为了他自己
and for his.
你什么都没说  但是我从你眼里看到了不屑
You say nothing, but I see defiance in your eyes.
这个眼神我看到过太多太多次了
That is a look I have seen many, many times.
那个大兵过来的时候
When the soldier comes,
当你看到他怎么死时  你就不是这个眼神了
when you watch how he dies, it will change you.
那时候你就会巴不得忘掉我
You will want to forget me then.
雷彻
Reacher?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
他们已经做好准备等着你了
They're ready for you.
他们自以为准备好了
They'd like to think so.
别过来  求你别过来  我不值得
Don't do this. Please don't do this. Not for me.
听着  海伦
Listen, Helen
他们抓到我之前是不会伤害你的
They're not gonna hurt you until they have me.
但是他们不会抓到的
And that's never going to happen.
听清楚了吗
You hear me?
你坚持住
You just hang in there.
我马上来救你了
'Cause I'm coming to get you.
快说你相信我
Now say you believe me.
我相信你
I believe you.
这主意太烂了
This was a bad idea.
快点啊  神枪手
Any time now, Gunny.
妈的
Shit.
你他妈在哪呢  神枪手
Where the hell are you, Gunny?
去死吧
Suck it!
您该走了
You should go.
把枪放下
Toss it.
我知道你在里边  爱默生
I know you're in there, Emerson.
有一件事我忽视了
It was staring me right in the face.
唯一不合理的那一点
The one piece that just didn't fit.
那枚硬币
The quarter.
没人会想到去搜停车计时器
Nobody would have thought to dump that meter.
连我也想不到
Not even me.
你冤枉我父亲了
You were wrong about my father.
我不会扩大声势的
I wouldn't make a big thing of it.
他是谁
Who is he?
那是神秘的二号人物
That's John Doe Number Two.
整场阴谋的策划者
The man on the grassy knoll. The thing under the bed.
人们称他为柴克
They call him the Zec.
柴克  囚犯
Zec? Prisoner.
你真名叫什么
What's your real name?
我出生在十月
I was born in October.
我数到十  就扣动扳机
When I get to my birthday, I'm gonna pull the trigger.
一  二
One. Two.
车罗维克  柴克・车罗维克
Chelovek. Zec Chelovek.
车罗维克
Chelovek?
车罗维克  人类
Chelovek? Human.
囚犯人类
Prisoner Human Being.
-这是你真名  -我只记得这么多
-That's your real name? -That is all I remember.
快报警
Call the police.
你刚才真打算开枪吗
Were you really going to shoot him?
我知道我不需要开枪
I knew I wouldn't have to.
只要看看这个人
One look at this guy
就知道他会不计一切代价地活下去
and you know he'll do anything to survive.
只要看看我就知道我不是在虚张声势
One look at me and you know I'm not bluffing.
对  这边有紧急状况
Yes, I have an emergency at...
好的  我稍等一下
Yes, I'll hold.
我们不着急
We're in no hurry.
您名叫囚犯  现在应该觉得回到家里了
With a name like yours, you're gonna feel right at home.
进监狱  在美国吗
Prison? In America?
是养老院吧  如果我真要进的话
A retirement home. If I go to prison at all.
你觉得自己逃得掉吗
You think you're gonna walk?
你是一个无家可归的流浪人
You are a homeless drifter
被控谋杀的通缉犯
wanted for murder.
而我
Meanwhile,
是一个在错误时间到了错误地点的老人
I am an old man in the wrong place at the wrong time.
多亏了你呀  还会有别的结果
Thanks to you, who is left to say otherwise? Who?
是的  您好  对  我这边有个紧急情况
Yes, hello? Yes, there's... I have an emergency.
我们就等着看到底谁进监狱吧
We'll see which one of us goes to prison.
外面大概死了三四人
There are maybe three, four people dead.
好吧
Okay.
猜我怎么说  都不进
My bet? Neither one.
你干嘛了
What did you do?
看不出来吗
What's it look like?
那真相怎么办
What about the truth?
这些真凶怎么办呢
What about getting the guys who really did this?
不将他绳之于法吗
What about bringing him to justice?
已经绳之于法了
I just did.
那怎么为巴尔洗脱罪名呢  还有你
What about clearing Barr? What about clearing you?
我相信你能办到的
I have faith you'll sort it out.
我听说你很受当地检察官的青睐
And I hear you have an in with the local D.A.
那你现在怎么办呢
But what happens to you in the meantime?
继续流浪  跟以前一样
I keep moving. Same as always.
等一下  那是我的车吗
Wait, is that my car?
这就是那位女士
This the lady?
海伦・罗丁  马丁・凯希
Helen Rodin, Martin Cash.
幸会
A pleasure.
你看起来真糟啊  大兵
You look like hell there, Army.
你刚刚问我怕不怕像巴尔一样的下场
You asked if I was afraid I'd end up like Barr.
我不怕
I'm not.
我怕变成他那个样子
I'm afraid I'll end up like this guy.
那边死了很多人  我们动身吧
There's a lot of dead bodies out here. So let's get to it.
-我们该走了  -等等  就这样吗
-We should probably go. -Wait. That's it?
就这么结束了吗
It's just over?
你会没事的  律师小姐
You'll be all right, counsellor.
不  如果我需要你怎么办  我怎么找到你
No. What if I need you? How will I find you?
你不需要我
You don't need me.
不再需要了
Not any more.
留下她电话  我们走吧
Get her number. Let's go!
我是海伦・罗丁  你的律师
I'm Helen Rodin, your attorney.
这次谈话受诉讼委托人权益保护
This conversation is protected by attorney-client privilege.
你明白我的意思吗
You understand what that means?
明白
Yeah.
警察今天没问你话吧
Now, the police didn't talk to you, did they?
没有我在场他们不能审问你
They're not allowed to do that without me here.
情况有多糟糕
How bad was it?
我杀了多少
How many did I...
这件事你一点都不记得了吗
You don't remember anything about the incident?
不记得
No.
但是我听到了外面护士跟警察的对话
But I could hear the nurses talking to those cops out there.
我甚至都不记得自己想要这么做
I don't even remember wanting to do it!
听着  我不打算申辩了
Look, I'm not gonna fight this.
如果他们说是我做的  那就是我做的
If they say I done it, then I did.
我之前做过一些事
I done things before.
我做过坏事
I did something bad.
坏得透顶
Real bad.
那是很久以前的事了
A long time ago.
而且我还逃脱了罪名
And I got away with it.
詹姆斯
James,
你熟悉这个地方吗
how well do you know this place?
非常熟悉
Pretty well.
你觉得你是怎么做的
And how do you think you would have done it?
我猜
I guess
我会把车停在高速公路上
I would have parked up on the highway.
那个时候太阳应该是在我身后
The sun would be at my back that time of day.
我有一辆货车
I got a van.
把枪架在后面
Set up in back.
不需要担心会留下弹头
Wouldn't have to worry about my brass.
做得干净利落
Get away real clean, too.
是这样的吗
That sound about right?
听起来很像你的作风
Sounds as if you know your stuff.
我忘了你名字
I forget your name.
我叫海伦
It's Helen.
海伦・罗丁
Helen Rodin.
你会没事的  詹姆斯
You're going to be okay, James.
我会保护你的
I am gonna take care of you.
你保护不了我
You can't protect me.
没人能
No one can.
为什么
From what?
谁要伤害你
From who?
有这么一个人
There's this guy.
他有点像个警察
He's a kind of cop.
至少他曾经是警察
At least he used to be.
他不在乎法律
He doesn't care about the law.
也不在乎证据
He doesn't care about proof.
只在乎什么是对的
He only cares about what's right.
我跟你讲话的时候看着我
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
他知道我的所作所为
He knows what I did.
他知道我身处何处
He knows where I am.
这个人给我一个承诺
And this guy, he made me a promise.
我说  闭嘴
I said, shut your mouth!
如果我再惹上麻烦
If I ever got in trouble again,
他会来收拾我
he'd be there.